whois.sc 2019-12-20

# DomainTools Privacy Policy

**Updated May 2019**

* * *

At DomainTools LLC (“ **DomainTools** ”), we appreciate your interest in our services, products, and websites (collectively, our “ **Services** ”). Your privacy is very important to us. This Privacy Policy sets out information about how we collect, store, process, transfer, and use personal data, which is data that relates to an identified or identifiable natural person (" **Personal Data** ").

* * *

### 1) Is DomainTools a data processor or a data controller?

Where DomainTools is the data controller of your Personal Data, we are responsible for, and control, the processing of that Personal Data. Where DomainTools processes Personal Data on behalf of another company (for example, where you receive access to the Services under a subscription purchased by your employer), DomainTools acts as a data processor. In that circumstance, you should consult with the other company to learn more about its privacy practices and your rights.

* * *

### 2) What Personal Data do we collect and how do we collect it?

DomainTools collects data in order to develop, offer, and support Services dedicated to research, cybersecurity, and intellectual property protection. In the context of our Services, we may collect Personal Data from or about you. This Personal Data is collected in several ways and may include:

#### Personal Data you provide to us directly.

You may provide us with Personal Data voluntarily in connection with purchasing our Services, registering for a DomainTools user account, requesting information or support from DomainTools via phone, email, mail, or our website, or attending a DomainTools webinar or event. We may collect your name, job title (if applicable), address, email address, phone number, information from correspondence with you, your account alias and password for user login, information related to the use of our Services, payment information such as credit card or other billing information, and additional Personal Data you provide to us. While you are free to choose what information you provide to us or whether you want to provide information to us at all, some information, such as your name, address, payment information, and information about your Services usage or subscription may be necessary for the performance of our contractual obligations. If you do not provide such information to us, you will not be able to license or use certain Services.

#### Personal Data collected via technology.

As you use our Services, we may collect Personal Data through the use of cookies and other technologies. For detailed information about our use of cookies, please see the section of this Privacy Policy entitled "What cookies do we use?"

#### Personal Data we receive from others.

We may receive Personal Data about you from third parties such as social media sites, law enforcement agencies, your employer (if you use Services through a DomainTools subscriber account provided by your employer), promotional partners, and other marketing vendors. This information may include your name, company and job title (if applicable), address, email address, and phone number.

#### Personal Data associated with the registration or maintenance of an internet domain.

We collect publicly-available domain and DNS related information (often referred to as Open Source Intelligence or OSINT) from entities tasked with coordinating the internet’s global domain name system. This information (“ **DNS related information** ”) may include the name, address, phone number, and email address of a domain registrant, administrative contact, or technical contact.

* * *

### 3) Why do we collect and use your Personal Data?

The reasons we collect and use Personal Data differ depending on the purpose of the collection.

#### We use your Personal Data in order to offer or provide Services to you.

If you license Services from DomainTools or contact us to request Services or Services support, we use your Personal Data to provide Services to you. Personal Data we use for this purpose includes information we need to contact you and communicate with you, information to provide you with individualized offers, information to manage and execute your requests, and information necessary to obtain payment.

#### We use your Personal Data when supported by legitimate business interests.

We may use Personal Data in connection with a legitimate business interest, such as to evaluate and review our business performance or to identify potential cybersecurity threats to our Services, networks, or systems. If necessary, we may also use your Personal Data to pursue or defend ourselves against legal claims. If you use our Services, we may use your Personal Data to provide and improve those Services.

We collect and use DNS related information that is publicly available at the time of collection, and that may contain Personal Data, to provide Services to users, to maintain and improve those Services, and to develop new Services. These Services include tools to help our users prevent, detect, investigate, or mitigate cybersecurity threats, fraud, and misuse; protect intellectual property rights; research the history of a domain; or contact the registrant, administrative contact, or technical contact of a domain.

#### We use your information after obtaining your consent.

In some cases, we may ask you to grant us separate consent to use your information, for example, in connection with our marketing campaigns. In that event, you are free to deny your consent or withdraw your consent at any time without any negative consequences. If you have granted us consent to use your information, we will use it only for the purposes specified in the consent. You may unsubscribe from our marketing communications at any time by sending an email to privacy@domaintools.com or clicking the “unsubscribe” link in communications you receive from us.

#### We use your information to comply with legal obligations.

We may be legally obligated to retain certain Personal Data.

We will only use your Personal Data for the purposes for which we have collected it. We will not use your Personal Data for other purposes. Your Personal Data will not be used for automated individual decision-making.

* * *

### 4) Does DomainTools share your Personal Data with third parties? 

We share your Personal Data with your consent or as necessary to provide you with Services you have requested or purchased. Additionally, we may share Personal Data with our affiliates; vendors working on our behalf; where required by law; to maintain the security of our Services; or to protect the rights or property of DomainTools. We also share DNS-related information obtained from publicly available sources via our Services to our customers and users. Specifically, we may share Personal Data in the following circumstances:

#### DomainTools Affiliates:

To support the maintenance and delivery of our Services, we may share Personal Data with our affiliate DomainTools SARL.

#### Service providers and advisors.

Third party vendors and other service providers may have access to your Personal Data if they perform services for us or on our behalf. These providers may support our marketing efforts (including sales outreach, communications management, and event support), provide business productivity solutions and applications to us (such as tools for messaging, email, and document creation, accounting and payment processing, or customer relations management), offer professional services (such as tax, accounting, or legal services), or assist with network or systems support, maintenance, and security. These third party vendors include: Aha! Labs Inc., Amazon Web Services, Inc., Authorize.Net LLC, Avalara, Inc., Bizible, Inc., BrightTALK, Inc., Cisco Systems, Inc., DiscoverOrg, LLC, DocuSign, Inc., Google LLC, LogMeIn Inc., Marketo, Inc., Oracle Corporation, Outreach Corporation, Pendo.io, Inc., Salesforce.com, Inc., Slack Technologies, Stripe, Inc., Tableau Software, Inc., Zendesk, Inc., and Zoom Information, Inc.

#### Purchasers and third parties in connection with a business transaction.

Personal Data may be disclosed to third parties in connection with a DomainTools-related transaction, such as a merger, sale, reorganization, financing, change of control or acquisition of all or a portion of our business, or in the event of a bankruptcy or similar proceedings.

#### Law enforcement, regulators, and other parties for legal reasons.

We may disclose Personal Data to third parties as required by law or subpoena or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) enforce our legal claims or to protect the security or integrity of our Services; or (c) exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of DomainTools, Services users, or others.

#### The public.

Certain Services make DNS related information available to the public without charge. Other Services, such as reporting, monitoring, and analysis of DNS related information are provided to registered customers for a fee.

* * *

### 5) How long do we keep your Personal Data?

We will store Personal Data as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which we collect it, in accordance with our legal obligations and legitimate business interests. We retain Personal Data related to a customer until the expiration of any legal retention requirement or limitations period for claims related to that relationship. We retain marketing-related information for potential customers until the conclusion of our relationship with that individual or the receipt of a request to delete such Personal Data. We retain DNS-related information for as long as it is used in connection with the delivery, maintenance, support, and development of our Services.

* * *

### 6) How do we protect your Personal Data?

We implement appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect your Personal Data against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, change, or damage, as well as any unauthorized access to or disclosure of Personal Data on our systems. All Personal Data we collect will be stored on secure servers. When you provide sensitive information to us (such as payment information when purchasing a Service via our website), we undertake to encrypt this information using secure socket layer (“SSL”) or similar technology. In order to benefit from these protections you must use an SSL-enabled web browser.

* * *

### 7) How do we safeguard your Personal Data when there is an international transfer?

Because DomainTools is located in the United States, Personal Data provided to us will be processed and stored in the United States. If you are in the European Union, Switzerland, or European Economic Areas, this may mean that your Personal Data will be stored in a jurisdiction that offers a level of protection that may, in certain instances, be less protective than the jurisdiction in which you reside.

For this reason, we have entered into guarantees to ensure appropriate safeguards. If we transfer information of individuals who reside in the European Union, Switzerland, or European Economic Areas to third parties outside of those jurisdictions and to countries not subject to regulations that are considered to provide an adequate standard of data protection, we will either enter into contracts that are based on the EU Standard Contractual Clauses with these parties or we will rely on our certification to the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. DomainTools complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. DomainTools has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>. As part of our participation in Privacy Shield, we are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the US Federal Trade Commission. If you have questions or concerns about our Privacy Shield certification, please contact us at the address identified in the section of this Privacy Policy entitled “How to contact us.” DomainTools has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to Judicial Arbitration and Mediation Services (JAMS), an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaints to your satisfaction, please contact or visit www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield for more information or to file a complaint. The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. In certain circumstances, the Privacy Shield Framework provides the right to invoke binding arbitration to resolve complaints not resolved by other means, as described in Annex I to the Privacy Shield Principles, available at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>. DomainTools remains responsible for any of your personal information that is transferred to third party agents or service providers that perform services on our behalf.

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with applicable law and this Privacy Policy.

* * *

### 8) What cookies and tracking technologies do we use?

We, and our third-party partners, automatically collect certain types of usage information when you visit our Services, read our emails, or otherwise engage with us. We typically collect this information through a variety of tracking technologies, including cookies, web beacons, embedded scripts, location-identifying technologies, file information, and similar technology (collectively, “tracking technologies”). You may use browser controls or tools made available by third parties to control tracking technologies.

#### What are Cookies?

Cookies are small text files that are downloaded to your device (such as a computer, tablet or mobile phone) when you visit a website. Cookies allow websites or ad networks to recognize a user's internet browser. This helps websites determine whether the browsing device has visited before.

#### What are Cookies used for?

Cookies not only help us understand how our Services are used, they let you navigate between pages efficiently, remember your preferences, and generally improve your browsing experience. Cookies can also help ensure that the marketing you see online is more relevant to you and your interests.

#### What types of cookies are used by DomainTools?

The types of cookies used on our Services can generally be put into one of the following categories: strictly necessary; analytics; functionality; advertising; and social media.

  * **Strictly Necessary Cookies.**  
These cookies are essential to the functionality of our Services. They enable you to move around the Services and use their features. Without these cookies, elements that are necessary for you to fully use our Services may not be available.

  * **Analytics Cookies.**  
TThese cookies collect information about how people use our Services. All of the information these cookies collect is grouped together to provide us with analytical information about how our Services are performing and how we can improve them.

  * **Functionality Cookies.**  
These cookies allow us to remember choices you make and tailor our Services to provide enhanced features and content to you. For example, these cookies can be used to remember your user name, language choice, country selection and requested Services.

  * **Advertising Cookies.**  
We may share or we may permit third-party online advertising networks, social media companies, and other third-party services to collect information about your use of our website over time so that they may play or display ads on our Services, on other devices you may use, and on other websites, apps, or services. Typically, though not always, the information we share is provided through cookies or similar tracking technologies, which recognize the device you are using and collect information, including click stream information, browser type, time and date you visited the site, and other information. These tracking technologies are used to deliver advertisements that are more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. These tracking technologies remember that you have visited a website and this information may be shared with other organizations, such as advertising partners.

  * **Social Media Cookies.**  
In order to enhance your internet experience and to make the sharing of content easier, some of the pages on our websites may contain tools or applications that are linked to third party social media service providers. These social media companies may recognize you and collect information about your visit to our Services, and they may set a cookie or employ other tracking technologies. Your interactions with those features are governed by the privacy policies of those companies.

#### How long will cookies stay on your browsing device?

The length of time a cookie will stay on your browsing device depends on whether it is a "persistent" or "session" cookie. Session cookies will only stay on your device until you stop browsing the website that has set the cookie. Persistent cookies will stay on your browsing device after you have finished browsing a particular website until they are deleted or until they expire.

#### How can I control cookies?

"First party cookies" are cookies that belong to us and that we place on your device. "Third party cookies" are cookies that are placed on your browsing device by another party when you visit our websites. Third parties who set cookies from our websites provide a service to us or a function of the website, but we do not always control how third party cookies are used. The third-party cookies on our websites are provided by Bizible, Google (including Google Ads, Google Marketing Platform, and Hire with Google), Marketo, TechTarget, Twitter, and Vimeo.

_Cookies and Flash cookies_. Many of the cookies we use are designed to help you get the most from our Services but if you do not wish to receive cookies, most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings in the "options" or "preferences" menu. Please note that if you choose to refuse cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality of our Services. Deleting or blocking cookies may not be effective for all types of tracking technologies. Although we do our best to honor the privacy preferences of our users, we are unable to respond to Do Not Track signals set by your browser at this time.

_Interest-based Advertising_. To learn about interest-based advertising and how you may be able to opt out of some of this advertising, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s online resources at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices), the Digital Advertising Alliance’s resources at [www.aboutads.info/choices](https://www.aboutads.info/choices), or guidance developed by the EU advertising industry called Your Online Choices at <https://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk>. Please note that opting out of receiving interest-based advertising through the NAI’s and DAA’s online resources will only opt out a user from receiving interest-based ads on that specific browser or device, but the user may still receive interest-based ads on other devices.

_Google Marketing Platform_. We use Google Marketing Platform to recognize you and link the devices you use when you visit our site or Service on your browser or mobile device, log in to your account on our Service, or otherwise engage with us. We share a unique identifier, like a user ID or hashed email address, with Google to facilitate the service. Google Marketing Platform allows us to better understand how our users interact with our Services and to tailor our advertisements and content to you. For information on how Google Analytics collects and processes data, as well as how you can control information sent to Google, review Google's site “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps,” located at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners>. You can learn about Google Marketing Platform’s currently available opt-outs, including the Google Analytics Browser Add-On, here <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>. We may also utilize certain forms of display advertising and other advanced features through Google Marketing Platform, such as Remarketing with Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, the Campaign Manager Integration, and Demographics and Interest Reporting. These features enable us to use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick advertising cookie) or other third-party cookies together to inform, optimize, and display ads based on your past visits to the Service. You may control your advertising preferences or opt out of certain Google advertising products by visiting the Google Ads Preferences Manager, currently available at <https://google.com/ads/preferences>.

* * *

### 9) What rights and choices do you have?

If you are a resident of the European Union and we hold your Personal Data, you have specific rights under applicable privacy law:

#### Right of access.

The right to obtain access to your Personal Data.

#### Right to rectification.

The right to obtain rectification of your Personal Data without undue delay where that personal information is inaccurate or incomplete.

#### Right to erasure.

The right to obtain the erasure of your Personal Data without undue delay in certain circumstances, such as where the personal information is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or processed.

#### Right to restriction.

The right to restrict us from processing your Personal Data in certain circumstances, such as where you contest the accuracy of the Personal Data.

#### Right to object.

You have a right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to processing based on our legitimate interests. You can object to marketing activities for any reason.

Additionally, EU residents have the right to lodge a complaint with their local data protection authority. Further information about how to contact your local data protection authority is available at <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>.

* * *

### 10) How to contact us

If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy or if you want to exercise your rights, please send an email to privacy@domaintools.com or write to us at: DomainTools, 2101 4th Ave, Suite 1150, Seattle, WA 98121. You may also contact our EU representative, DomainTools SARL, at domaintoolsSARL@domaintools.com or by mail at 21, rue Levon Leval, L-3372 Leudelange, Luxembourg.

* * *

### 11) Data Protection Officer

For inquiries regarding DomainTools’ activities, you may contact our Data Protection Officer:

DomainTools, LLC  
2101 4th Avenue Suite 1150  
Seattle, WA 98121  
Attn: Data Protection Officer  
privacy@domaintools.com

* * *

### 12) Online Privacy Policy Updates

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. When we change the Privacy Policy in a material manner, we will let you know and update the “last updated” date at the top of this page. Please review our policies regularly as updated policies will apply to your future use of our Services.
